{
	"maps": [
		"Bleasdale Farmhouse",
		"Brownstone High School",
		"Camp Woodwind",
		"42 Edgefield Road",
		"Grafton Farmhouse",
		"Maple Lodge Campsite",
		"Prison",
		"10 Ridgeview Court",
		"Sunny Meadows Mental Institution"
	],
	"ghosts": [
		{
			"type": "Banshee",
			"evidences": [
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Fingerprints",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Will target only one player at a time.",
			"weakness": "Can sometimes be heard wailing with the Parabolic Microphone.",
			"characteristics": [
				{
					"text": "You can recognise the Banshee by the sound that it can make inside of a parabolic mic.",
					"question": "Did you hear a screech trough the Parabolic mic?",
					"expected": true,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": true,
					"showOnly": true
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "Demon",
			"evidences": [
				"Freezing Temperatures",
				"Fingerprints",
				"Ghost Writing"
			],
			"strength": "Can initiate hunts more often.",
			"weakness": "Crucifix effectiveness is increased to 5m against one.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Goryo",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Fingerprints",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Can only be seen interacting with D.O.T.S. through a camera when nobody is nearby.",
			"weakness": "Tends to wander away less from its ghost room.",
			"characteristics": [
				{
					"text": "The Goryo's D.O.T.S can only be seen on the Camera. If you saw it without a Camera it's not a Goryo!",
					"question": "Did you see D.O.T.S without a camera?",
					"expected": false,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": false
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "Hantu",
			"evidences": [
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Freezing Temperatures",
				"Fingerprints"
			],
			"strength": "Lower temperatures allow the Hantu to move faster.",
			"weakness": "Warmer areas slow the Hantu's movement.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Jinn",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Freezing Temperatures",
				"Fingerprints"
			],
			"strength": "Travels at faster speeds if its victim is far away.",
			"weakness": "Cannot use its ability if the site's fuse box is off.",
			"characteristics": [
				{
					"text": "A Jinn can't turn off the breaker. You could hide and keep the breaker on to see if the ghost will eventually turn it off.",
					"question": "Did it turn off the breaker?",
					"expected": false,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": false
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "Mare",
			"evidences": [
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Spirit Box",
				"Ghost Writing"
			],
			"strength": "Has an increased chance to attack in the dark.",
			"weakness": "Turning the lights on will reduce the chance of an attack.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Myling",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Fingerprints",
				"Ghost Writing"
			],
			"strength": "Has quieter footsteps during a hunt.",
			"weakness": "Produces paranormal sounds more frequently.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Obake",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Fingerprints"
			],
			"strength": "May leave fingerprints that disappear quicker.",
			"weakness": "Has a small chance of leaving six-fingered handprints.",
			"characteristics": [
				{
					"text": "There is a rare chance that the Obake will leave a Fingerprint on the door with six fingers! So count the amount of fingers on your fingerprints!",
					"question": "Did you see a fingerprint with six fingers?",
					"expected": true,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": true,
					"showOnly": true
				},
				{
					"text": "There is a rare chance that the Obake will leave a double Fingerprint on light switches!",
					"question": "Did you see a fingerprint with two fingers on a light switch?",
					"expected": true,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": true,
					"showOnly": true
				},
				{
					"text": "There is a rare chance that the Obake will leave five fingerprints (a hand) on prison doors and keyboards!",
					"question": "Did you see a fingerprint with five fingers on a prison cell door or keyboard?",
					"expected": true,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": true,
					"showOnly": true
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "Oni",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Freezing Temperatures",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Increased activity and ghost events.",
			"weakness": "An Oni's increased activity makes them easier to find.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Onryo",
			"evidences": [
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Spirit Box",
				"Freezing Temperatures"
			],
			"strength": "A flame extinguishing can cause an Onryo to attack.",
			"weakness": "The presence of flames reduces the Onryo's ability to attack.",
			"characteristics": [
				{
					"text": "If the ghost starts a hunt while there are lit candles in the room it cannot be an Onryo.",
					"question": "Did the Ghost start a hunt in a room with lit candles?",
					"expected": false,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": false
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "Phantom",
			"evidences": [
				"Spirit Box",
				"Fingerprints",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Looking at a Phantom will lower the player's sanity considerably.",
			"weakness": "Taking a photo of the Phantom will cause it to briefly disappear.",
			"characteristics": [
				{
					"text": "If the ghost starts a hunt while there are lit candles in the room it cannot be an Onryo.",
					"question": "Did it disappear after taking a photo in a ghost event or the photo labeled \"Ghost\" has no distortion?",
					"expected": true,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": false,
					"showOnly": true
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "Poltergeist",
			"evidences": [
				"Spirit Box",
				"Fingerprints",
				"Ghost Writing"
			],
			"strength": "Capable of throwing multiple objects at once.",
			"weakness": "Becomes powerless with no throwables nearby.",
			"characteristics": [
				{
					"text": "A Poltergeist is the only ghost that can throw multiple items at once.",
					"question": "Did it throw multiple items at the same time?",
					"expected": true,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": true,
					"showOnly": true
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "Raiju",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Moves faster near electrical devices.",
			"weakness": "Disrupts electronic equipment from further away when it hunts.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Revenant",
			"evidences": [
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Freezing Temperatures",
				"Ghost Writing"
			],
			"strength": "Can travel significantly faster if a player is spotted during a hunt.",
			"weakness": "Moves very slowly when not chasing a player.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Shade",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Freezing Temperatures",
				"Ghost Writing"
			],
			"strength": "Being shy makes it more difficult to locate and obtain evidence.",
			"weakness": "Less likely to hunt if multiple people are nearby.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Spirit",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Spirit Box",
				"Ghost Writing"
			],
			"strength": "None.",
			"weakness": "Smudge sticks are more effective, preventing a hunt for longer.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "The Mimic",
			"evidences": [
				"Spirit Box",
				"Freezing Temperatures",
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Fingerprints"
			],
			"strength": "Can mimic the abilities and traits of other ghosts.",
			"weakness": "Will present Ghost Orbs as a secondary evidence.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "The Twins",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Spirit Box",
				"Freezing Temperatures"
			],
			"strength": "Either Twin may start a hunt, though not at the same time.",
			"weakness": "Will often interact with the environment at the same time.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Wraith",
			"evidences": [
				"EMF 5",
				"Spirit Box",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Does not leave UV footprints after stepping in salt.",
			"weakness": "Will become more active if it steps in salt.",
			"characteristics": [
				{
					"text": "If it steps in Salt and then doesn't show footprints while you can hear it stepping around in the room it's a Wraith!",
					"question": "Did it have footpints after stepping in salt and walking around?",
					"expected": false,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": false
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "Yokai",
			"evidences": [
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Spirit Box",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Talking near the Yokai will anger it, increasing the chance to attack.",
			"weakness": "Can only hear voices close to it during a hunt.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Yurei",
			"evidences": [
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Freezing Temperatures",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Has a stronger effect on sanity.",
			"weakness": "Smudging the Yurei's ghost room will reduce how often it wanders.",
			"characteristics": [
				{
					"text": "A Yurei can fully close a door that is near you without performing a ghost event. So keep doors open!",
					"question": "Did it fully close a door?",
					"expected": true,

					"successShow": true,
					"errorShow": true,
					"showOnly": true
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "Deogen",
			"evidences": [
				"Spirit Box",
				"Ghost Writing",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Deogen constantly sense the living. You can run but you can't hide.",
			"weakness": "Deogen require a lot of energy to form and will move very slowly.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Moroi",
			"evidences": [
				"Spirit Box",
				"Freezing Temperatures",
				"Ghost Writing"
			],
			"strength": "The weaker their victims, the stronger the Moroi becomes.",
			"weakness": "Moroi suffer from hyperosmia, weakening them for longer periods.",
			"characteristics": []
		},
		{
			"type": "Thaye",
			"evidences": [
				"Ghost Orbs",
				"Ghost Writing",
				"D.O.T.S Projector"
			],
			"strength": "Upon entering the location, Thaye will become active, defensive and agile",
			"weakness": "Thaye will weaken over time, making them weaker, slower and less aggressive",
			"characteristics": []
		}
	]
}